Guide to the Legal documents - Kentucky, Virginia, North Carolina, Georgia, 1750-1879.
Legal documents - Kentucky, Virginia, North Carolina, Georgia
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Legal documents - Kentucky, Virginia, North Carolina, Georgia, 1750-1879.
4780
.4 cubic feet.
Financial Records, Legal Documents, Manuscripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Legal documents include wills, estate inventories, indentures and other land documents, summonses and other court documents, and accounts. Many relate to the ownership of slaves.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Legal documents include wills, estate inventories, indentures and other land documents, summonses and other court documents, and accounts. Many relate to the ownership of slaves.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Slavery--United States.; Slavery--Kentucky.; Slavery--Virginia.; Slavery--North Carolina.; Slavery--Georgia.
Places:
Kentucky--Social life and customs.; Kentucky--History.; Virginia--History.; Virginia--Social life and customs.; North Carolina--History.; North Carolina--Social life and customs.; Georgia--History.; Georgia--Social life and customs.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Form and Genre Terms:
Legal documents.; Wills.; Indentures.; Legal instruments.; Judicial records.; Summonses.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Kentucky 1781-1865
  - Two Documents. Virginia Court Case About Land in Kentucky, 1786-1792. Document About Sale of A horse and Wagon, ca. 1781, North Carolina, 1781, 1786-1792 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Slander Case Affidavit. Jane Hogan vs. Samuel Davis. Lincoln County, KY, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Power of Attorney to Sell Kentucky Lands. Thomas Cunningham, James Adams, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Removal of a Lawsuit. Green Clay. Lexington, Kentucky, 1797 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Whiskey Accounts. Kentucky - Lexington, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Three Documents. Levington Summons 1799. Levington Summons 1799. Fair Fax County, Virginia Summon 1798, 1798, 1799 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Summons - Mason County 1799. Summons - Mason County 1800. Summons - Mason County 1801. Summons - Mason County 1807, 1799-1801, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Receipt for Land Purchase. James Taylor, 1805. Deed of General Warranty (Land) James Taylor, Campbell County, Kentucjky, 1814, 1805, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Indentures (2). Land in Ohio, 1801, 1806 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Power of Attorney George and Hugh Mercer. James Taylor. Campbell County, Kentucky, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Richard Hickman. Lieutenant Governor. Clay County, Kentucky Land Grant, 1812 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Autograph Letter. Edmond Penn, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Deposition. Abraham Clay. About a slave named Amy Galbreath. Slavery. Mentions Cornwallis, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Indenture. John Fowler. Includes Slaves. Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Declaration. Hume vs. Childers. Horse Thief/Murder Case, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Writ for Payment of Debt. Jane Clarke - Griffen Theobalds. Grant County, Kentucky, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Power of Attorney. Samuel Adams, Sr. Shelby county, Kentucky, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Document. Deed of Sale. Harrodsburg, Kentucky, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Estate Inventory. Includes Slaves. Laurence Egbert. Mercer County, Kentucky, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Decree of Division of Property Including Slaves, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Estate Inventory. Slaves. William Fields. Mercer County, Kentucky, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Will - Elizabeth Adams, 1833. Will - Phebe Fishback, 1837. Frees a Slave., 1833, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Estate Inventories (2). Mercer County, Kentucky, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Indenture. William Holt and Joseph Holt. Transferring Property Including a Slave, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Will-Hugh Evans. Mentions Slaves, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Estate Inventories (2), 1845, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ALS From W. Washington to Taylor Thornton, New Post, Kentucky, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Deposition From a Physician About Treating Slaves, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Document by Governor Beriah Magoffin to Forgive Payment. Mercer County, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Campbell Circuit Court. Newport, Kentucky. Order to Sell "Unruly" Slaves. Also Franklin County, Ohio, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Oath of Office "Will not give aid to the rebellion" School Trustee, April 1, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Illustrated Price List. C.P. Barnes and Brother, Louisville, Kentucky (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Verginia 1750-1879
  - Estate Document, Printed. Fairfex County, Virginia, 1750 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Will. Alexandria, Virginia, 1756 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Complaints. Loudon County, VA 1759; Mason County, VA 1801; Campbell County KY 1815; Levi Todd 1798, 1759, 1798, 1801, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Land Sale. Loudoun County, VA, 1762 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Indenture. Loudoun County, VA, 1762 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Service Indenture, Leesburg, VA; Land Transfer Loudon county, VA, 1762, 1804 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Indenture For Servent; Land Rental, Loudoun County, VA, 1763 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Land Indenture, Virginia, 1766 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - George Washington Documents: Bill of Sale - Washington Signature as Witness, Loudon County 1766; Warrant for Surveying Land for Washington, 1785; Land Survey 1787, 1788, 1766, 1785, 1787, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Indenture, Loudoun County, VA, 1770 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Landindenture, Loudoun County, 1773 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Land Transfer, Fairfex County, VA, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Indenture, Fayette County, VA 1783; Land Office Military Warrant 1784, 1783, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Indentures, Fairfax County, VA, 1783, 1786 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Summons (3): Lincoln County 1783, Madison County 1791, Lincoln County 1791, 1783, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Indenture, Fairfax County, VA, 1785 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Land Indentures: Fairfax County 1786, king George County 1791, 1786, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Land Indenture, Loudon County, VA. "Blue Ridge" Deed, 1787 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Indentures. Henry Lec, Westmore County VA, 1789, 1796 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Land Transfers (2), Fairfax County, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Land Transfers (2), Fairfax County, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Ship Contract 1794, Proof or Imported Spirits 1804, Land Office Military Warrant 1810, 1794, 1804, 1810 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Marriage Indenture, Fairfax VA, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Peposition, Burke County 1795, Virginia Militia 1812, 1795, 1812 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Indenture, Potomac Company and Canal of Great Falls, Fairfax County, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Land Transfer, Fairfax County VA, 1799 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Affidavit, Loudoun County, 1804 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Deeds of Gift (2). Samuel Adams, Jr. Fairfax County VA, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Indenture Fairfax/Loudoun Counties VA, 1810 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Estate Settlement Including Slaves, Fairfax County VA, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Amy Kilbread Trial Testimony, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Sale of Slaves, Culpepper VA, 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - ALS George F. Washington to Gen. James Taylor, Waverly, VA, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Settlement Document, Fairfax County VA, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Citizenship Declaration (Ireland) 1855; Complaint, Fairfax County VA 1846, 1846, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Accounts, Patrick County, VA, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Memorandum About an Interview With General Lee. May 9, 1862. General Henry A. Wise (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - State of Virginia Definition of Colored Person and Indians. Printed, ca. 1867 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Tobacco Sale Broadside. Danville, VA. Thos. L. Poindexter and Son, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- North Carolina 1824-1865
  - Listing of Goods for Sale. Roberts Jaffray and Co. Fayetteville, NC, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Marriage Licenses, Lincoln and catawbe Counties, NC, 1845-1869 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Announcement of Opening of Boys' School in Melville, NC, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Pardon by Henry Clark for Wesley Gray, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Insurance Policy 1853, Signed Over 1857, 1853, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Confederate States Receipt, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Abstract of Forage, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Georgia 1862-1872
  - Receipt for Purchase of Slave for $1000. Atlanta, Georgia, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Clothing Appropriation Georgie Volunteers 1865, Confederate Visitor's Permit 1862, 1862, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Clothing Appropriation, Georgia, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Appointment and Receipt. Quartermaster/Agent Clothing. Georgia, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Letter Refusing Any More Drafts Written on Advertisement for Grady's Company. To Ira Foster and Son. Savannah, GA, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Freight Receipt. Hawkinsville Agency. Macon and Brunswick Railroad Co. (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Place Unknown 1806-1846
  - Slave Receipt, 1806 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Inventory, 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Estate Sale, Includes Slaves, 1844, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 87)